* * * *
        
    * * * *
        
    * * * *

Get Started by Finding a Local Center

* Find Location

Privacy Policy
==============

**Effective Date: August 23, 2023**

**Last Updated:** **August 23, 2023**

 _**For our California Notice at Collection, please click**_ [_**here**_](#_PERSONAL_WE_COLLECT).

This Privacy Policy describes our practices related to personal information collected, used, and disclosed by Mathnasium LLC (“Mathnasium,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) through our online and offline services, including the Mathnasium.com website, our mobile applications, and our online learning platform, Mathnasium@home (collectively, the “Services”). This Policy may not encompass all personal information collected or processed by individual tutoring centers, which are independently owned and operated franchises. Additional policies may apply in other contexts and to other relationships you may have with us. For example, we have separate notices for California job applicants and employees.

By using our Services or otherwise providing personal information to us, you agree to our [Terms of Use](https://www.mathnasium.com/terms-of-use) and our privacy practices as described in this Policy. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the “Last Updated” date at the top of this Privacy Policy.

**Contents**

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT & WHY WE COLLECT IT

In this Policy, “personal information” means information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with you. Personal information does not include information that is publicly available, de-identified, or aggregated.

Generally, we collect the following categories personal information in connection with providing the Services, which we use for the business or commercial purposes shown below:

| **Category of Personal Information** | **Categories of Sources** | **Purposes for Collection** |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Identifiers**, including real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, IP address, email address, account name, social security number, driver’s license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers | Directly from you or someone you know<br><br>Automatically when you use our Services<br><br>Advertising networks<br><br>Internet service providers<br><br>Data analytics providers<br><br>Social networks<br><br>Vendors that help us to provide our Services<br><br>Affiliates<br><br>Our franchisees | To provide you with requested Services<br><br>Communicating with you<br><br>Customer service<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of the Services<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity<br><br>Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services<br><br>As part of our application process for potential franchisees, and relationship with current franchisees |
| **Personal Records**, including name, signature, social security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or other financial information, or health insurance information<br><br>_This category includes the information described in Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)._ | Directly from you or someone you know<br><br>Advertising networks<br><br>Data analytics providers<br><br>Social networks<br><br>Vendors that help us to provide our Services<br><br>Affiliates<br><br>Our franchisees | To provide you with requested Services<br><br>Communicating with you<br><br>Customer service<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of the Services<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity<br><br>Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services<br><br>As part of our application process for potential franchisees, and relationship with current franchisees |
| **Characteristics of protected classifications** under federal or California law, including age and date of birth, gender, military or veteran status, marital status, citizenship | Directly from you or someone you know<br><br>Affiliates<br><br>Our franchisees<br><br>Data analytics providers<br><br>Social networks | To provide you with requested Services<br><br>Customer service<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services<br><br>As part of our application process for potential franchisees, and relationship with current franchisees |
| **Commercial information,** including records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies<br><br>This category includes the schools your child attends, school grade, registration date, enrollment information, progress reports, learning plans, survey data, attendance information, and other information relating to your student’s enrollment at one of our centers | Directly from you<br><br>Automatically when you use our Services<br><br>Advertising networks<br><br>Internet service providers<br><br>Data analytics providers<br><br>Social networks<br><br>Vendors that help us to provide our Services<br><br>Affiliates<br><br>Our franchisees | To provide you with requested Services<br><br>Communicating with you<br><br>Customer service<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of the Services<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity<br><br>Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services<br><br>As part of our application process for potential franchisees, and relationship with current franchisees |
| **Internet or other electronic network activity information,** including Internet or other similar activity, browsing history, search history, information on a consumer's interaction with a website, application logs, device data and registration, social media account information or advertisements | Automatically when you use our Services<br><br>Advertising networks<br><br>Internet service providers<br><br>Data analytics providers<br><br>Social networks<br><br>Vendors that help us to provide our Services | To provide you with requested Services<br><br>To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of the Services<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity<br><br>Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services |
| **Geolocation data** | Automatically when you use our Services<br><br>Advertising networks<br><br>Internet service providers<br><br>Data analytics providers<br><br>Social networks<br><br>Vendors that help us to provide our Services | To provide you with requested Services<br><br>To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of the Services<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity<br><br>* Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services |
| **Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information** | Directly from you / during a Mathnasium session | To protect the safety and security of students and instructors<br><br>To ensure quality of our sessions<br><br>For internal education and training purposes |
| **Professional or employment-related information** | Directly from you | As part of our application process for potential franchisees, and relationship with current franchisees<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| **Inferences** used to create a profile reflecting a consumer’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes | Drawn from the other categories of personal information we collect | To better understand how users access and use our Services, to improve the Services, to respond to user desires and preferences, auditing, and for other research and analysis<br><br>Marketing, advertising, and promotions<br><br>To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of the Services<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity<br><br>Tailoring our content or otherwise personalizing the Services<br><br>As part of our application process for potential franchisees |

 The categories of personal information we collect include the following categories of sensitive personal information.

| **Category of Sensitive Personal Information** | **Categories of Sources** | **Purposes for Collection** |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Social Security, driver’s license, state identification card, or passport number | Directly from you | As part of our application process for potential franchisees, and relationship with current franchisees |

We may also collect, use, and disclose personal information as required by law, regulation or court order; to respond to governmental and/or law enforcement requests; to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interfering with our (or others’) rights or property; to support any actual or threatened claim, defense or declaration in a case or before any jurisdictional and/or administrative authority, arbitration or mediation panel; or for other purposes described in any other privacy notice or with your consent. Additionally, we may use and disclose personal information to third parties in connection with a sale, assignment, merger, reorganization, or other corporate transaction relating to all or part of our business.

#### INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY

As indicated in the chart above, we collect some types of personal information automatically when you use our Services. For example, we use cookies and other tracking technologies (such as web beacons) to collect and store information about your interactions with our website, including information about your browsing behavior. Our website also supports third-party cookies placed by our service providers and third parties, such as advertising partners.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**. Cookies are small files that a website transfers to your device through a web browser that enable the site’s or a third party’s systems to recognize your device and capture and remember certain information. Web beacons (also known as tracking pixels) are tiny graphics embedded invisibly on a webpage or in an email that may be used to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited certain pages, and to understand usage patterns. In general, our website uses cookies and other tracking technologies as follows:

* Where necessary to run our website
    
* To optimize the functionality of our website
    
* For analytics purposes
    
* For purposes of ad targeting and marketing
    
* To determine if our email messages have been opened and acted upon

Cookies vary in how long they last. “Session cookies” terminate shortly after you terminate your internet session. “Persistent cookies” are stored on your device until a set expiration date. We use both session cookies and persistent cookies on our website.

Most web browsers accept cookies by default, but you may be able to adjust your browser settings to remove or reject cookies. If you do not want to have cookies placed on your device, you should adjust your settings within our cookie preference center or set your browser to refuse cookies before accessing our website. Please review your browser’s Help menu for instructions, or visit [https://allaboutcookies.org/](https://allaboutcookies.org/) for more information about cookies.

**Analytics**. We use analytics tools including Google Analytics to analyze how you interact with our website. This software may collect information such as your IP address, location, operating system, access time, duration of visit, and actions you take on our website. Google Analytics is owned and controlled by Google LLC. Data collected by Google is subject to its privacy policy. You may opt-out of having your website activity made available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics browser add-on, available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Session Monitoring**. We may also use third-party analytics tools such as Mouseflow to track visitor click/touch, movement, scroll, and keystroke activity on our website. When you interact with us online, information related to your browsing behavior may be collected by us and our service providers. To opt out of Mouseflow, please click [here](https://mouseflow.com/opt-out/).

**Online Advertising**. We collect some information about you in order to target advertisements to you when you browse the internet or use social media. To set your preferences with respect to the use of advertising cookies on our website, please scroll down to locate the "Cookies Settings" button.

You can personalize the ads you receive or opt out of ads from Google by visiting the [Google Ads Settings page](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). For more information about the use of Bing Ads or Microsoft Advertising on our website, please review the [Microsoft Privacy Statement](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement). Additional options for opting out of interest-based advertising can be found at: [youradchoices.com/appchoices](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices), [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1), and [optout.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/).

**Do Not Track Signals**. Your web browser may have settings that allow you to transmit a “Do Not Track” signal when you visit various websites or use online services. Like many websites, our website is not designed to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from browsers. To learn more about “Do Not Track” signals, visit [allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

#### How Long We Keep Your Personal Information

We keep the categories of personal information described above for as long as is necessary for the purposes described in this Notice or otherwise authorized by law. This generally means holding the information for as long as one of the following apply:

* Your personal information is reasonably necessary to manage our operations, to manage your relationship with us, or to satisfy another purpose for which we collected the information;
    
* Your personal information is reasonably necessary to carry out a disclosed purpose that is reasonably compatible with the context in which the personal information was collected;
    
* The personal information is reasonably required to protect or defend our rights or property (which will generally relate to applicable laws that limit actions in a particular case); or
    
* We are otherwise required or permitted to keep your information by applicable laws or regulations.

Where personal information is used for more than one purpose, we will retain it until the purpose with the latest period expires.

#### HOW WE DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION

The following chart summarizes the ways in which we may disclose the categories of personal information we collect to our affiliates, service providers, and contractors for business or commercial purposes:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Category of Personal Information** | **Purposes for Disclosure** |
| Identifiers | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, processing payments, supporting our promotions, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Auditing, related to ad impressions<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Personal Information described in Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e) | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, processing payments, supporting our promotions, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Auditing, related to ad impressions<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Characteristics of protected classifications | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, processing payments, supporting our promotions, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Commercial information | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, processing payments, supporting our promotions, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Auditing, related to ad impressions<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Auditing, related to ad impressions<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Geolocation data | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, processing payments, supporting our promotions, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Auditing, related to ad impressions<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in providing technical, analytical, and, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |
| Professional or employment-related information | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in providing technical, analytical, and, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf) |
| Inferences | Performing services on our behalf (e.g., assisting us in delivering content, supporting our promotions, and providing communications, technical, analytical, web hosting, cloud hosting, and other services on our behalf)<br><br>Providing advertising and marketing services (except for cross-context behavioral advertising)<br><br>Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, non-personalized advertising<br><br>Auditing, related to ad impressions<br><br>Ensuring security and integrity of personal information<br><br>Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality<br><br>Detecting, investigating, or protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity |

#### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

This section provides additional disclosures for California residents under the California Consumer Privacy Act (the “**CCPA**”). California job applicants can find applicable disclosures here \[link to CA Applicant Notice\].

**Sales and Sharing of Personal Information**. We do not sell personal information in exchange for money. However, some of the ways in which we share personal information for advertising, certain types of analytics, or with our franchisees and affiliates may be considered “sales” or “sharing” under California law. Listed below are the categories of personal information we share for purposes of cross-context behavioral advertising or otherwise “sell,” as that term is defined under California law:

* Identifiers
    
* Personal Records
    
* Commercial information
    
* Internet or other electronic network activity information
    
* Geolocation Data
    
* Inferences

The types of third parties to which personal information is sold or shared are third-party advertisers, some analytics vendors, and our franchisees and affiliates. The purposes for which we sell/share this information include: showing you relevant ads while you browse to internet or use social media; marketing, advertising, certain types of analytics, or similar purposes; and providing operational, analytical, and other support for our franchisees. We do not have actual knowledge that we sell or share the personal information of consumers under 16 years of age. We do not sell or share personal information obtained for text messaging purposes - including personal information obtained for opt-in consent purposes - with any third parties for those third parties' own marketing purposes.

California residents can opt out of the sale or sharing of their personal information by clicking here: Cookie Settings  
You may also opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information through an opt-out preference signal, such as the Global Privacy Control. If you choose to use a browser-based opt-out signal, you will be opted out of cookie-based sales or sharing of personal information, and will need to turn it on for each browser you use. To submit a request to opt out of offline sales and sharing, please use our [webform](https://www.mathnasium.com/ccpa-request-form).

**Right to Know**. California residents have the right to request more information regarding:

* The categories of personal information we have collected about you, including:
    
    * The categories of sources from which the personal information was collected
        
    * Our business or commercial purposes for collecting, selling, or sharing personal information
        
    * The categories of recipients to which we disclose personal information
        
    * The categories of personal information that we sold, and for each category identified, the categories of third parties to which we sold that particular category of personal information
        
    * The categories of personal information that we disclosed for a business purpose, and for each category identified, the categories of recipients to which we disclosed that particular category of personal information
        
* The specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.

**Right to Delete**. California residents have the right to request the deletion of personal information we collected from you, subject to certain exceptions. Where we use deidentification to satisfy a deletion request, we commit to maintaining and using the information in deidentified form and will not attempt to reidentify the information.

**Right to Correct**. If you believe that personal information we maintain about you is inaccurate, you may submit a request for us to correct that information. Upon receipt of a verifiable request to correct inaccurate personal information, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to correct the information as you direct.

**Right to Limit Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information**. We do not use sensitive personal information for purposes to which the right to limit use and disclosure applies under the CCPA.

**Submitting Requests Relating to Your Personal Information.** If you are a resident of California, you have the right to submit certain requests relating to your personal information as described above. To exercise any of these rights, please submit a request through our [webform](https://www.mathnasium.com/ccpa-request-form) or call us at 877-601-MATH (6284). Please note that, if you submit a request to know, request to delete, or request to correct, you may be asked to log into your account (if you have one) or to provide 2-3 pieces of personal information that we will match against our records to verify your identity. You may designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf; however, you will still need to verify your identity directly with us before your request can be processed. An authorized agent may submit a request on your behalf using the [webform](https://www.mathnasium.com/ccpa-request-form) or toll-free number listed above.

**Right to Non-Discrimination for the Exercise of Your Privacy Rights**. If you choose to exercise any of your privacy rights under the CCPA, you also have the right not to receive discriminatory treatment by us.

**California’s Shine the Light Law**. California consumers may request a list of the third parties to which we have disclosed personal information, as defined under California Civil Code Section 1798.83(e) (a/k/a the “Shine the Light Law”), during the preceding calendar year for third-party direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.mathnasium.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and include “California Shine The Light Request” in your email in addition to your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code.

#### INTERNATIONAL VISITORS

 If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that Mathnasium is based in the United States and the information we obtain through www.mathnasium.com will be transferred to and stored on our servers in the United States. You acknowledge that your personal information will be processed in the United States or in other jurisdictions, which may have data protection laws and regulations that are different from the laws in your country of residence. We maintain separate websites for other countries in which we operate. Additional or different policies may apply. 

#### INFORMATION RELATING TO CHILDREN

We do not knowingly collect personal information through our online Services from anyone under the age of 18 without first obtaining parental consent. In the event that we learn that an individual under the age of 18 has directly provided us with information without parental consent, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information from our database.

#### SOCIAL FEATURES

Our Services may permit you to interact with another website or online service, such as enabling you to “like” Mathnasium on another website or “share” content from our Services with other websites (“Social Features”). If you choose to “like” or “share” content or post information using Social Features, that information may be publicly displayed, and others may have access to certain information about you and your use of the Services. Similarly, if you interact with us through Social Features, we may have access to information about you (for example, if you “like” or “follow” our page on another website). Please note that if you mention or comment about Mathnasium or our Services in your post on a social media platform, that platform may allow us to publish your post on our Services.

#### EMAIL PREFERENCES

If you no longer want to receive our promotional email communications, you can unsubscribe by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link found in our commercial email messages. If you opt-out of our promotional emails, we may still send you email messages related to your account or any Services you request from us. Unsubscribing from our promotional emails will not affect the level or quality of service we provide to you.

#### Information About Online Chats

Our Services include online chat features to assist with answering questions and providing you with relevant information. When you participate in an interactive chat, either with a virtual or live agent, the contents of the chat may be captured and kept as a transcript. By using an online chat feature, you understand that our vendors may process the information obtained through the chat feature in order to provide services on our behalf.

#### DATA SECURITY

We have implemented reasonable measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. Although we use reasonable efforts to safeguard information, transmission via the Internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of your information collected through the Services.

#### CONTACT US

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or treatment of personal information by Mathnasium, please contact us by emailing [\[email protected\]](https://www.mathnasium.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), calling us at (877) 601-MATH (6284) or mailing us at:

Mathnasium LLC

5120 W Goldleaf Cir., Ste 400

Los Angeles, CA

90056-1661

Help Your Child Discover Their Math Potential
---------------------------------------------

##### We have over 1,000 centers nationwide. Get started now. It’s as easy as:

* Find a location
* Get a math skills assessment
* Talk to your center director about the customized learning plan for your child

©2024 Mathnasium LLC. All rights reserved.

[See More Reviews ](javascript:void(0);)
